Samuel Osei Kwakye

Ghana



kwakyesamuelosei@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/samuel-osei-kwakye-48674b131

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in Python (Programming Language), Databases, JavaScript, Angular, AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, and Web Services. Strong engineering professional with a BSc in IT focused on Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications, Computer Programming from the University of Ghana.

Programming Languages: Python, Javascript, Go

Tech Stacks: Flask, Angular, Javascript, Typescript, Vue, Vuex

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

API Specs: REST

Infrastructure: AWS, Heroku, Netlify, DigitalOcean

Containerization: Docker, Kubernetes Continuous Integration: Github Action

Other Tools/Services: Git

Domains: E-commerce, Logistics, Transportation, Education, Finances

Languages: English

Please feel free to reach out via email, at kwakyesamuelosei@gmail.com for more inquiries.

Experience



Software Engineer

GRUNDFOS

Jan 2022 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Working together with an awesome team - Grundfos Future Lab 1.

Developing ground-breaking impact solutions that contribute to SDG #6 and #13, (clean water & sanitation and taking action to combat climate change)

turntofil Software Engineer

turntabl

Oct 2019 - Jan 2022 (2 years 4 months)

Worked as part of the Engineering team to deliver projects that exceeded clients' expectations.

Software Engineer

Morgan Stanley

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020 (11 months)

Worked as part of the API Engineering team to deliver projects that exceeded clients' expectations.

Google Africa Certification Scholarship 2019 Recipient

Google

Jun 2019 - Jan 2020 (8 months)

Software Engineer

Nsano

Jan 2017 - Sep 2019 (2 years 9 months)

Worked in the different engineering team to deliver minimum viable products for their clients

Internship Trainee

University of Ghana Computing System

May 2016 - Aug 2016 (4 months)

Troubleshooting network issues

Splicing of fiber optic cable

Setting up new network labs

Education

University of Ghana

BSc in IT, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications, Computer

Programming

2014 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

- in Learning Node.js LinkedIn
- Building RESTful APIs with Node.js and Express LinkedIn
- in Node.js: Securing RESTful APIs LinkedIn

Skills

Python • JavaScript • Databases • Angular • React • Vue • TypeScript • Javascript • Redux • Vuex